TAYLOR FOSTER

Senior Character Animator | FPS Specialist

SUMMARY

Award-winning Character Animator with 11+ years of experience in developing compelling animations for popular FPS games, played by millions. Equipped with expert skills in Maya, Unreal Engine 4/5 and team mentoring. Recognized for consistently raising animation quality standards and driving gameplay experience improvements. Now seeking to bring my creative talent to an ambitious studio as it builds its new FPS IP.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Character Animator

2018 - Present

Bellevue, Washington

Developed and implemented character animations for critically acclaimed FPS titles, mentored team members, ensured high-quality animation standards.

- Developed vision and direction for character animation, which resulted in a 20% increase in overall user experience
- Directed team of 6 animators and developed their skills, resulting in a more efficient and creative work environment.
- Spearheaded the prototyping and implementation of new combat sequences, leading to replayability and increased player involvement.

Lead Animator

2014 - 2018

Epic Games

Seattle, Washington

Created and engineered character animations, improved gameplay experience through innovative techniques, collaborated with cross-functional teams.

- Successfully developed over 100 reactive and satisfying game animations, enhancing game appeal and replayability
- Implemented structured quality standards for animation, increasing overall game
- Developed 30+ unique character designs, which improved user engagement by 20%.

Junior Animator

2011 - 2014

Electronic Arts

Seattle, Washington

Responsible for assisting in the creation and refinement of character animations, working to maintain high and consistent quality across games.

- Assisted in the development and implementation of over 50 character models, improving overall visual game appeal.

 Contributed to team testing and reviewing, improving overall animation quality by 15%.
- Gained hands-on experience working with Unreal Engine, significantly contributing to the production of several successful game titles.

EDUCATION

Master of Fine Arts in Computer Animation

2009 - 2011

University of Washington

Seattle, Washington

Bachelor of Fine Arts in Animation

2005 - 2009 Valencia, California

California Institute of the Arts

LANGUAGES

English

Native ••••

Japanese

Advanced • • • • •

STRENGTHS

Creative Problem Solver

diagnose animation challenges solutions, improving overall team performance by 25%.

Strong Mentorship

inclusive, educational environment that resulted in a performance.

Detail Oriented

Track record for producing highquality, meticulous works that enhance gameplay experience

SKILLS

Maya Expertise · Unreal Engine 4/5 ·

Animation · Quality Assurance ·

Team Management · Prototyping ·

Character Design

CERTIFICATION

Advanced Character Animation

Unreal Engine 4 Mastery: Create Multiplayer Games

Achieved a professional command over Unreal Engine 4 through an extensive course of Epic Games, honing skills specific to multiplayer game development.

PASSIONS

Game Development

latest game development technology and tools, constantly updating my skillset for maximum productivity